Guide to the University of Chicago Mathematical Club Records 1893-1941
University of Chicago Library
University of Chicago. Mathematical Club. Records
1893-1941
1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Mathematical Club was established January 5, 1893 in order to provide a forum for graduate students in mathematics. Papers were presented and discussed by the faculty of the Mathematics and Astronomy Departments, and, occasionally by graduate students and visiting scholars. The Club Records contain programs of meetings (1893-1894), and notes on lectures delivered (1896-1903). The collection also includes programs from the Junior Mathematical Club (1905-1941).
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Historical Note
The Mathematical Club was established January 5, 1893 in order to provide a forum for graduate students in mathematics. Papers were presented and discussed by the faculty of the Mathematics and Astronomy Departments, and, occasionally by graduate students and visiting scholars.
Scope Note
The Mathematical Club Records contain programs of meetings (1893-1894), and notes on lectures delivered (1896-1903). The collection also includes programs from the Junior Mathematical Club (1905-1941).
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
University of Chicago. Dept. of Mathematics; University of Chicago. Mathematical Club; University of Chicago-History; University of Chicago-Societies, etc; Mathematics -- Study and teaching (Higher)
INVENTORY
- Mathematical Club and Seminar, programs of meetings, January 5, 1893-August 28, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Mathematical Club Records, October 12, 1896-March 12, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Mathematical Club Records, April 16, 1897-July 23, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Mathematical Club Records, July 30, 1897-August 10, 1897 (Summer Quarter) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Mathematical Club Records, October 16, 1897-December 3, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Mathematical Club Records, December 17, 1897-April 29, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mathematical Club Records, May 27, 1898-December 16, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mathematical Club Records, January 1, 1899-June 9, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Mathematical Club Records, July 14, 1899-December 14, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Mathematical Club Records, January 4, 1900-May 18, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Mathematical Club Records, July 20, 1900-December 7, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Mathematical Club Records, January 11, 1901-May 29, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Junior Mathematical Club Records, October 6, 1905-June 8, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- "Record of mathematical club," notebook, 1910-1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "Historical Sketch and List of Programs" for the junior mathematical club, by Professor H.E. Slaught, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 2)